[SPEAKER_02]: that little thing there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I usually start out by asking you fellows where you grew up and if you did any ball playing as a kid, you know, what your family thought about it and so on.
[SPEAKER_02]: So could you tell me a little bit about your early years?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, my first year I was in the
[SPEAKER_00]: Lexington, Kentucky in the Bluegrass League.
[SPEAKER_00]: OK. What year would that have been?
[SPEAKER_00]: That was in 1920.
[SPEAKER_02]: OK. Was your dad a ball player?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had a couple of uncles who were ballplayers, not professional ballplayers, but they played.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you play high school ball or sandlot ball around here?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, I played sandlot ball around.
[SPEAKER_02]: How old were you when you first played ball as a kid?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, as long as I can remember.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was eight or ten years old, I imagine.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just in the playgrounds around town?
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was before Little Leagues and so forth.
[SPEAKER_02]: You hit the ball farther than the other kids, I'll bet.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I don't know about that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Some of them, that's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: OK. And you played high school ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: And who signed you to your first professional contract?
[SPEAKER_02]: You remember?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, an old newspaper man named Newt Holland.
[SPEAKER_00]: Holland?
[SPEAKER_00]: Holland.
[SPEAKER_00]: Holland, H-O-R-N. OK.
[SPEAKER_00]: advertising manager at the National Tennessean.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he sent me, at one time he was an old catcher, he played in the Bluegrass League, and he defended, I think I was 17 years old at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he sent me to Lexington, and I stayed in Lexington a little while,
[SPEAKER_00]: And they got in bad financial circumstances and didn't pay off, so.
[SPEAKER_02]: What year did you go with Lexington?
[SPEAKER_02]: Twenty-three or?
[SPEAKER_02]: Twenty-four.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did Horn see you, where'd he see you play?
[SPEAKER_02]: All around Los Angeles, Nashville.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was a paper boy around Tennessee in there, so yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, what'd you think about signing a professional contract?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I was all for it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd been working in the printing office.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where I ran the printing company, and that's who I was with when I was in baseball, amateur baseball around Nashville.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I was with the Texans for a while, and after that I went up in the
[SPEAKER_00]: Holden, West Virginia, the coal fields up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Old Bill Schumacher was the old first baseman that managed it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is this the same year or the next?
[SPEAKER_02]: Same year.
[SPEAKER_02]: 24?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, 24.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was the name of that town again?
[SPEAKER_02]: Holden, West Virginia.
[SPEAKER_02]: Holden?
[SPEAKER_02]: Holden, H-O-L-D-E-N. Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: They were in the Mountain State League, or?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, they was in, that's a club.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, is that?
[SPEAKER_00]: That was a company, coal company.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: And in the following year... Well, tell me, how'd you do at Lexington that year?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it's been so long ago I forgot to tell you the truth about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was a catcher and an outfielder and... Hit pretty well, as you recall?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I hit pretty well there.
[SPEAKER_02]: You were a home run hitter, right, in the minor leagues?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I hit quite a few home runs in the minor leagues, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you like being away from home that first year or did it matter to you?
[SPEAKER_00]: It didn't matter too much.
[SPEAKER_00]: I enjoyed it.
[SPEAKER_00]: You enjoyed playing ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did it pay you much?
[SPEAKER_00]: Not too much.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think I got a...
[SPEAKER_00]: I was supposed to get $100 a month at Lexington and I think I only got expenses the whole time I was there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Let's see how it sounds so far.
[SPEAKER_02]: The reason why I asked you about how you felt being away from home is
[SPEAKER_02]: Yesterday I talked to Kent Greenfield, you know Kent, up in Guthrie.
[SPEAKER_02]: He went up in 1922 or 23.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was terribly homesick.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a lot of ability.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just threw it away.
[SPEAKER_00]: He admits it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit against him a lot of times.
[SPEAKER_00]: We come back to Nashville in the winter, and we go up to Kentucky afterwards.
[SPEAKER_00]: The kid pissed around up there after the season's over, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pretty fast, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, he was.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a great curveball.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was fancy.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a lot of ability.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said the bottle got him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was his big trouble.
[SPEAKER_02]: Too bad.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, uh.
[SPEAKER_02]: OK, you're up in Holden, then.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you work at the coal company there very long?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I was supposed to repair coal cars.
[SPEAKER_00]: We mostly played cards behind the shack somewhere.
[SPEAKER_00]: It is different.
[SPEAKER_00]: Four or five professional ball players was on that ball club, including Bill Schumacher.
[SPEAKER_02]: Anybody else you can remember?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, a boy named Ewing used to be the divisive around here.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he's dead now, of course.
[SPEAKER_02]: I come from West Virginia.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm in northern West Virginia, but I don't know where Holden is.
[SPEAKER_00]: You don't?
[SPEAKER_00]: I never heard of Holden.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's right up in the little cold southern part.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess it's about 10, 15 miles from Logan.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, we know that area.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's coal mining country, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, it's all up through there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did the Lexington team fall?
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that what you said?
[SPEAKER_02]: That's why you went up there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the following year,
[SPEAKER_00]: 1925, OK. 1925, I went to Knoxville, South Atlantic League.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I started touring.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was in Knoxville for a couple of years.
[SPEAKER_02]: How did you happen to go with them?
[SPEAKER_02]: Was there anybody you know somebody there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I came through Chattanooga that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Strang Nicklin was the owner and manager of the Strang Nicklin ball club.
[SPEAKER_00]: Strang Nicklin?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Sammy Strang Nicklin.
[SPEAKER_02]: Joe Engle wasn't there?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I was along for Joe Engle.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played with Joe Engle.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a real promoter, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, he was.
[SPEAKER_02]: Okay, so that's how you got up to Knoxville then, through this Strang Nicklin?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I went there, and Colonel Moffett was manager of the ball club.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I played with Salisbury.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's in the Eastern Shore League?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's somewhere along there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was that in 25 also?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I was in 25 and 26.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was with Malcolm most of the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was, what classification was that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Class B ball, South Atlantic League.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you owned by anybody, any major league club at all?
[SPEAKER_02]: Not at that time, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you hoping you were going to go up, or did you think about it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I expected to, but I think for me, I was, I guess the second year in Knoxville, I was sick.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the following year I went to Alexandria, Virginia.
[SPEAKER_02]: What league was that?
[SPEAKER_00]: I think that was a Virginia league, maybe.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll tell you the truth.
[SPEAKER_00]: There were so many little old leagues back then.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I went from then to the Southeastern League.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think Selma, Alabama, in the Southeastern League.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was with them a short while, and I sold to Shreveport in the Texas League.
[SPEAKER_00]: The same year, I sold to Cleveland in the American League.
[SPEAKER_02]: How did that come about?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you remember how Cleveland got a hold of you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I was playing in St. Augustine, Florida, and sand about a half a foot deep.
[SPEAKER_00]: And old Dutch Hoffman, old ball player, he was the second baseman around New Orleans.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was managing the club, and I came in after one inning.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had a rough day that day, and I was coming, and I started taking my shoes off.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when they used to dress at the hotel, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I'm going back to the United States.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I'm getting out of here.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, well, wait a minute now.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we finished that ballgame.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, I got another place for you to go.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm going to send you to the tactics league.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll get you out of the United States.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went to Shreveport.
[SPEAKER_00]: Art Thaler was the manager there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Art Thaler?
[SPEAKER_02]: Thaler.
[SPEAKER_00]: Thaler.
[SPEAKER_00]: P-H-E-L-E-N, Phelan.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was only with Shreveport the rest of that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: About a month, I guess, I sold Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did Phelan know somebody in Cleveland?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: How did they find out about you down here in Shreveport?
[SPEAKER_00]: Satnick overlooked me.
[SPEAKER_00]: He bought me from Shreveport.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think at that time, Shreveport was having a rough time making ends meet, you know, in that league down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's when I played with Pete Kilduff, that fellow.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the second baseman.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he must have been doing very well at Shreveport.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I had a great, the latter part of that season, I was doing great.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think the day he bought me I hit three home runs, a triple, and a double.
[SPEAKER_00]: At Beaumont, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: That must have been one of your better days.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess that was my best day.
[SPEAKER_02]: 17 total bases.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, something like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: How did you travel in all these lower leagues?
[SPEAKER_02]: Small leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: Traveled all night and played all day.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sleeping in the best hotels, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Halftime, we just sat in the bus.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, went to Texas League, where we traveled by train down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's like me going to heaven.
[SPEAKER_00]: The leagues I've been in.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did they give you much money to live on or to feed yourself?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I forgot how much.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think it was $2 a day, meal money.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was pretty good meal money at that time.
[SPEAKER_02]: I bet you had a lot of fun riding those buses, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, we did, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: All night long or whatever?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was part of the state league for a little while that same year.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is all 27, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, I think it's the first part of 2007, I was in the Carpenter State League.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Bill Pierce was the manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bill used to hit the ball quite often.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd sit in the back of the bus and get paralyzed.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'd say, anybody can play ball if you get a nice rest in it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Takes a good ball player to play it at the same time without a nice rest.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you play a lot of cards and things in the game?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Trains and buses.
[SPEAKER_00]: We all played for fun, though, because we didn't have much money.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, how did you feel when you heard you were going up to Cleveland?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know why.
[SPEAKER_02]: Must have been a big thrill, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: That was a great feeling at the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I finished the season that year with Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who, that was Jack McAllister?
[SPEAKER_00]: Jack McAllister was the manager there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And who were some of the players on the team?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you remember?
[SPEAKER_00]: There was Joe and Luke Sewell, and George Burns, and Lou Fonseca, and Charles Jameson.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right after the year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Speaker was the manager that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had to resign under a cloud, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then just when Jack McAllister took it over,
[SPEAKER_02]: He only lasted one year, is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Jack McAllister, I think he had the second part of the club over the following year.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when the Nickel Plate Railroad bought Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they went out and bought a lot of ball players.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Nickel Plate Railroad?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Alva Bradley?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when they first bought that Cleveland ball club.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they went out and tried to get a good ball club.
[SPEAKER_00]: established ballplayers at that time, Bill Falk.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh yeah, Vince Falk.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was McAllister a very good manager?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I didn't see that much of him, I suppose.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't think too much of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was a good baseball man, no doubt about that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a scout later on in baseball for a long time.
[SPEAKER_02]: Homer Summa?
[SPEAKER_00]: Homer Summa was in Wright Field when I first went there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I always liked that name, Homer Summa.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he's a good ball player.
[SPEAKER_02]: Johnny Hodapp was a ball player there.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's from Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_02]: I tried to interview him, but he was busy putting people, burying people.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's still a funeral visitor.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he still is.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's very nice in the phone, but he says, I can't set a time to meet you because I might have a funeral.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I wasn't able to talk to him.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know that he wanted to, but he
[SPEAKER_01]: said he was tied up.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I've talked to Luke Sewell.
[SPEAKER_02]: He lives up in Akron.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm going to see Joey Sewell a couple of days from now down in Tuscaloosa.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Joe was a wonderful person.
[SPEAKER_00]: And what Luke was, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was both of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Joey's going up to the Hall of Fame on next Monday.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he'll make it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He should make it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't think he's won.
[SPEAKER_00]: He only struck out four times or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: I wonder why he struck out so few times.
[SPEAKER_02]: He must have had a good eye, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a good eye, yes.
[SPEAKER_02]: What about your first game up there at Cleveland?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you remember that at all?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you remember anything about it?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was on the road in Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember I hit a ball over Flagstaff's head in center field.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he played so deep and everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, well, you can say one thing in baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, you're the only guy ever hit someone over his head.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Because he played so deep, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's a deep center field there, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you remember who you were pitching or batting against?
[SPEAKER_00]: I forgot who the pitcher was at that time.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it was quite a way to break in.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was Pinky Schaffner on the team when you were with him at all?
[SPEAKER_00]: Pinky Schaffner?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, the pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know Pinky.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's from Boston, isn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he lives up out of Cleveland now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he does?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he's retired up there in a little village on the lake.
[SPEAKER_02]: He told me that the first time he faced a game, he faced Babe Ruth, I guess, with a basic loader and struck him out, something like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's a wild story.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he could have.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I played against Ruth that same year in 26.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was her great year, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I remember Joe Sewell telling me at the time, he said, John, today you're going to see the best left-hand pitcher in baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, who is that?
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, yeah, well, you'll see.
[SPEAKER_00]: The ball game started, and I started the ball game right to the end.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when Yankees had that great ball club, you know, and Herb Pinnock was a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, first time at bat, he threw me a little Dickie curveball, hit a line drive, right field, Ruth made a good catch on him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said to him, next time up, same thing happened.
[SPEAKER_00]: Line drive, left, right field, Ruth made another good catch.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a little white glove, that rooster, and everybody used to think he was a great outfielder.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I said to myself, I said, gee, this guy's a left-handed up here, I ain't gonna have trouble.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I went, we were rockin' along, the last inning, he had his big 3-2 or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had to cuff him in on, and I was ahead of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he threw me another little dinky curveball inside.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit it with a foul ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he broke a little sharp cut on the outside.
[SPEAKER_00]: I quick like that and strike two.
[SPEAKER_00]: I took that one.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the next one, I just batted the next pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: That exploded.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the curveball exploded.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was called out, strike three.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I go in the clubhouse and Joe says, see what I mean, John?
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, yeah, I understand.
[SPEAKER_02]: See what I mean?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was good, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he doesn't pitch good enough to win.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was the whole thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't try to make you hit the ball all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: When the men on the bases, though, he kind of slowly, he kept you from hitting it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you have a chance to bat against Walter Johnson?
[SPEAKER_02]: It was about his last year there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went to Washington when he was the manager in Washington.
[SPEAKER_00]: And after hitting against him in hitting practice, the guy that was pitching that day didn't have anything.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the truth.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: He just flung a ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: If you hit him, you hit anybody in the league.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's what they said.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's what they used to say about Johnson.
[SPEAKER_02]: I thought the batting practice pitchers were supposed to just lob it up, but he didn't do that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he was just, according to Johnson, he was just lobbing it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they say, I've talked to ballplayers that's been up there for some time, good ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_00]: They say he was the greatest.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Fast, isn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: Dr. Groves in the league that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, Zepty was the main one at that time, a strikeout man.
[SPEAKER_02]: How'd you like him to hit against you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'm not too good.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit a lot of foul balls off of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's about the best I could do.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, if Johnson had been with a winning team, he'd have had a lot more victories than he had.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he would have.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's too bad to be with a second division club.
[SPEAKER_00]: He ain't got to be as always one to nothing or something like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: He'd be bad.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that's when Jonathan was a man then, and the next year, Cronin was a man.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, let me look at your record here.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't follow it through here after you got to Cleveland here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I went from Cleveland to Baltimore.
[SPEAKER_02]: You were with Cleveland for how long then?
[SPEAKER_00]: I belonged to them for three years.
[SPEAKER_02]: Three years?
[SPEAKER_02]: 27, 28 years.
[SPEAKER_02]: 27, 28, and I belonged to them.
[SPEAKER_02]: You didn't play much in 28.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you with them all season?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I was just with them in the spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's Bill Evans was his young man at the time, second father of the man.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, let me go to Baltimore.
[SPEAKER_02]: They had a pretty good outfield.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tough to break into, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Was it Washington?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, the Indians in 28.
[SPEAKER_02]: Wasn't their outfield?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah, that one was.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the reason they let you go, probably.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, they had Abel and Jamison still, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jamison, River Falls.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sumner was still there, and Bob Seeds.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was that kind of disappointing, then, to go back down to Baltimore?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, not exactly.
[SPEAKER_00]: You liked to play ball, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: I wanted to play somewhere, so I went to Baltimore.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was a good amount of league ball player in the National League at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: There were batters on the major league teams then.
[SPEAKER_00]: There were.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when Razor had Jack Dunn still owned his wife.
[SPEAKER_00]: He died the year before that, and his wife was the owner of the ball club.
[SPEAKER_00]: When I first went there, Mason was the manager and that's when I first met Joe Heiser.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a great year there in 30.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you with him in 30?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: He hit about 63 home runs or something?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he hit 50 some more.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think I hit 40 some more.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I played with Joe again in Minneapolis.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's when he hit 69.
[SPEAKER_02]: 69 in Minneapolis.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit 43 in Minneapolis, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: The same year he hit these?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not the same year.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is later than that.
[SPEAKER_00]: The following year.
[SPEAKER_00]: The other year there, I was in Minneapolis, latter part of, let's see, 30.
[SPEAKER_02]: Not a time ago.
[SPEAKER_00]: 35, somewhere along there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was in Baltimore two years, then I sold to Washington.
[SPEAKER_00]: Washington sent me to Chattanooga on option.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where I met Joe England.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I stayed with him a couple of years.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was a fool around there and couldn't get away from it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he finally let me go to Mike Kelly in Minneapolis.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tell me about Roger Peckinpah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you remember much of him at all?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, not too much.
[SPEAKER_02]: You weren't with them that long?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I was with them in the spring training, the football games, and playing.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did Cleveland still own you when you were sent down to Baltimore?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd already sent me out twice.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was in Albany one year.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when I was with the team.
[SPEAKER_00]: In Eastern Lake?
[SPEAKER_00]: Eastern Lake.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bill McCoy was the manager.
[SPEAKER_02]: Maybe that was in 28.
[SPEAKER_02]: You went to Baltimore in 29.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's about the year.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went to Baltimore in 29.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went to Baltimore in 30.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was there 30 and 31.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then they showed me Washington.
[SPEAKER_00]: Washington sent me to Chattanooga in 32.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think I hit about 390 in Auburn that whole year.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't hit too many home runs.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit a lot of doubles that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had a big ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: Were you pretty fast?
[SPEAKER_02]: Leg out hits or steel bases?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, not especially.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit a lot of doubles.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was Baltimore a pretty big ballpark?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the left field was kind of short and the right field was about 320 or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you hit all fields or did you pull the ball?
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit all fields.
[SPEAKER_00]: You didn't hit for home runs necessarily?
[SPEAKER_02]: Or did you swing for home runs?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, there's thirty-four home runs the first year I was a ball boy, and about the same amount the following year.
[SPEAKER_00]: But when you were a bat, did you have your mind on a home run or on a base hit?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: You just went with the pitch, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Just went with the pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit the ball, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: Not like they do it today, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Today, that ball wouldn't play with us now, though.
[SPEAKER_00]: Those little bitty boys hit the ball out of the park now.
[SPEAKER_02]: Pretty lively.
[SPEAKER_02]: 1930, though, the ball was lively, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I think it was.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was the year Hack Wilson hit a lot of home runs.
[SPEAKER_02]: Hauser hit his 63, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, who was the manager just down at Baltimore then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Chris Mason.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was Eddie Onslow?
[SPEAKER_00]: That was an old Yankee, old third baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was Eddie Onslow with the team then?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was at Uber 4 then, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: He lives up in Ohio, not too far from me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I talked to him a couple times.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then finally, he gonna let me go to Mike Kelly in Minneapolis.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went there and stayed there a bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I finished the season there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was with them the whole season the following year.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's when I was sold to the Chicago Club.
[SPEAKER_02]: It says you were back with Washington in 34 for a few games.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was with Chattanooga.
[SPEAKER_00]: They brought me up to Washington for a few games.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about Joe Cronin?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I thought a lot of Joe Cronin.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a good manager.
[SPEAKER_02]: He knew his baseball, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a good baseball man.
[SPEAKER_00]: Good player.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sometimes good players don't make good managers.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a good manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: Boston must have thought so, because they gave a lot of money for him at that time.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, they sure did.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't get along with Griffith.
[SPEAKER_00]: I saw Griffith and Joe wanted me, wanted to keep me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was doing pretty good in Washington.
[SPEAKER_00]: Joe wanted to keep me, but Eagle had a chance to win down in the Southern League.
[SPEAKER_00]: I want to make sure it's still going, sorry.
[SPEAKER_00]: I couldn't keep the way of men going.
[SPEAKER_00]: We went to Pennant the first year.
[SPEAKER_00]: First year down there in 32.
[SPEAKER_00]: We went to Pennant, Chattanooga.
[SPEAKER_00]: But Harley Balsam was there too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Same year.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's when Cleveland bought him, brought him up to 33.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about playing here in Nashville?
[SPEAKER_02]: You never belonged to the Nashville club.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, for a short while.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played, well, I finished the season that year with the Cubs, and the next year, postseason, then I went to the Summer of San Francisco with Joe Mardi deal.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I hurt my knee.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played a short while with San Francisco, I hurt my knee pretty bad, and I just sat on the bench the rest of the season.
[SPEAKER_02]: Joe Marty was going to be another Joe DiMaggio, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he was supposed to be.
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't quite make it.
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: It wasn't too many Joe DiMaggio.
[SPEAKER_00]: His brother was as good of a power fielder as he was, though.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dominick.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dominick, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played with Dominick in San Francisco.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's a worth-looking ball player.
[SPEAKER_00]: I saw him in spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: He throw a sidearm curveball, he'd fall down.
[SPEAKER_00]: And old Dewey, the manager of the club, I said, that guy, I said, he's going to hit a hundred in this league.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, he hit over 300.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, you don't know what he's got.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he did hit over 300.
[SPEAKER_00]: Next year, he hit 380, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about the old ballpark here in Nashville?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, the Chopperdale?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, that's the park that had all the hills?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you play out there in right field?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I played right field.
[SPEAKER_02]: How do you play a field still like that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, as I said, that's just in Bankman or something like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, it is?
[SPEAKER_02]: Something like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: I thought they had.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had one in Boston at one time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Their field in Boston was worse than the one in Nashville.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it's a pretty short right field in Nashville, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had big high chances.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think it's 200.
[SPEAKER_00]: some field, but it was not very far.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, that year, so I came back to Nashville here, and I think, they had given one down here in Nashville, that short right field, you know, and I was training in Little New Orleans, you know, with a fielder there for about three or four years, and
[SPEAKER_00]: Larry was the general manager and manager of New Orleans.
[SPEAKER_02]: Gilbert?
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Larry Gilbert.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got me ahead in the half.
[SPEAKER_00]: I couldn't hit the ball while he was feeling low.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was swinging the ball and my knee jumped out on me.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when I hurt my knee in San Francisco.
[SPEAKER_00]: Meanwhile, I played for Hornet Bay one time, and he was managing Baltimore again at that time.
[SPEAKER_02]: How'd you like him?
[SPEAKER_00]: I liked Hornet Bay.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought he was a good manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot of people didn't like him because he was a little strict.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was always nice to me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went there.
[SPEAKER_00]: So my knee was still bad, I couldn't help him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd sit around warming up pitchers and stuff like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Warmed over the rest of that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: In the following year, I had my knee off.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went to Vanderbilt Hospital out here to see Dr. Regan.
[SPEAKER_02]: What year did this be now, 36?
[SPEAKER_00]: Actually, I was with the Cubs in 35 and 36.
[SPEAKER_00]: Went to Frisco at 30.
[SPEAKER_00]: When I went to, 37 when I went to San Francisco.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I went back.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I must have heard it that year then, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the following year I went to, I went to, well, I came back to Nashville to have them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't expect to train anymore.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I told them, I said, go out and see Dr. Regan if I see need.
[SPEAKER_00]: see what he says about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I went out to the Vanderbilt Hospital there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He sat me down in a chair, grabbed hold of my foot, and worked my knee.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, you got three injuries there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can fix one of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can still fix it the way you play ball if you want to.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, well, I want to.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so he operated on my knee, took that cartilage out.
[SPEAKER_00]: So meanwhile, Jack, Tommy Thompson, he used to be with Washington.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pitcher used to be with Washington.
[SPEAKER_00]: He is over at Baltimore.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was Hornets' coach at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Jack, I forgot his name.
[SPEAKER_00]: The following year he went to Philadelphia as the young manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jack...
[SPEAKER_02]: The Phillies or the...
[SPEAKER_00]: The Phillies.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he told me to get my release from Baltimore if I'd manage the club for him the next year.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I agreed with it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got my release from me, sent it to me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I met him in Cincinnati for the meeting.
[SPEAKER_00]: The club he promised me he didn't have.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he said, well, John, you got your release.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, if you can bail yourself, go ahead and get another job.
[SPEAKER_00]: He offered me some little bit of town, some little league or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I couldn't do that too much.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't want that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so Johnny Fredericks was managing Portland, Oregon.
[SPEAKER_00]: I met him at a meeting in Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: He asked me what I was doing.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm a free agent.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm not doing anything right now.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, well, how about coming with us?
[SPEAKER_00]: And I explained to him about my knee and everything like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I don't know if I can help you or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I just had my knee operated on during the winter.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, I've been working out, running with baseball shoes on.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, well, how about signing a contract with us?
[SPEAKER_00]: And so I said, OK.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was at Portland then.
[SPEAKER_00]: At Portland, Oregon.
[SPEAKER_00]: About 38, 38 season?
[SPEAKER_00]: I think it was 38 or 39, 38 I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I stayed with Portland for 46 or 7 years.
[SPEAKER_00]: I stayed there about 8 years, about 8 years.
[SPEAKER_00]: How was the need?
[SPEAKER_00]: It wasn't like, it wasn't what you call 100% but I could, it didn't bother me too much, I could play pretty good.
[SPEAKER_02]: You were with them longer than any other team then, weren't you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I believe I was.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was with Portland longer than anything.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was there about... let's see...
[SPEAKER_00]: I played under Marv Owen there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He won a...
[SPEAKER_00]: Played during the war then, huh, out there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Portland saw me as a Seattle.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was Bill Skip.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's my last year that I played in the Coastal League.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then next year, I tried to get my release from Seattle.
[SPEAKER_00]: I figured all the ballplayers would be coming back from out of the Army, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was wasting my time going out there, as old as I was.
[SPEAKER_00]: They wouldn't let me go at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I started operating a restaurant here in Nashville.
[SPEAKER_00]: and the side left me semi-released to me.
[SPEAKER_02]: You had a restaurant?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you have this before this time?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: You just bought it then?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I didn't have it.
[SPEAKER_02]: So that's about it, I imagine.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did you do in the off-seasons?
[SPEAKER_00]: Work anywhere?
[SPEAKER_00]: There wasn't many things to do in the off season, the ball player, because he wasn't in the business or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you like to hunt and fish?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I used to do quite a bit of hunting, not too much fishing.
[SPEAKER_00]: I tried to fish, but I never could do much good.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was a bad fisherman.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was a pretty good hunter, though.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, then I was waiting for
[SPEAKER_00]: I tried that in the kiddie league up there, but that stuff, all them boys could come back from the Army, you know, and you got to tell them everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: And in the Army, they was told to do this, do that, do that, and they went by that in baseball, too, when they got out.
[SPEAKER_02]: Let me just check and see how we're doing here.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tell me how you
[SPEAKER_02]: You got along with the umpires?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got along pretty good with most of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some of them I didn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was a kind of hothead, I guess, a little bit when I was in baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never could get as good as I thought I would.
[SPEAKER_02]: You get thrown out of many games?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, not too many.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I guess I get thrown out two or three times a year, something like that, or three or four.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you think the umpires do a pretty good job overall?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yes sir, I sure do.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's been so long ago since, I don't know how they're doing now, but I know back in that time there was a lot of good umpires back in those days, in the minor leagues and the big leagues too.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you recall in your career anything really funny, any funny things happening during games?
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, crazy things are always happening in ballgames.
[SPEAKER_02]: Does anything stand out?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's a whole lot of things.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't tell how many things happened.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't recall right offhand.
[SPEAKER_02]: Nothing stands out, you know?
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd like to get some of these.
[SPEAKER_02]: funny story, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, well, I don't remember any right now, but I know there must have been a lot of them.
[SPEAKER_02]: Every time I go to a game, I think to myself, what will I see in this game that never happened before?
[SPEAKER_02]: Something always happens, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's really crazy.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's one of the great attractions of the game, so much can happen.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about a big thrill?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that's one of the biggest thrills I ever had in baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went in to pitch against Dizzy Dean when he was good at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there was two men on.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he struck me out on three pitches.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Charlie Green was managing the Cubs then.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, Charlie, let me finish this game.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I'll beat him for a day's overview, just let me stay in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that was about the seventh inning.
[SPEAKER_00]: Something just told me I was.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I came back up.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was two outs.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was just, there was two hitters in front of me.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was Hack and Hartnett.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Hack hit a ball back to Dears on the mound.
[SPEAKER_00]: He missed the ball, hit him in the chest, bounced off, he beat it out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hardy was the next hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hit a ball in a hound.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just kind of got over Collins' head in the first base.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was two on.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I knew Hardy was going to pitch me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Diz come all that way, that fastball with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't jump about that much.
[SPEAKER_00]: I bless all that told me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, John, any time a guy's fast and his ball's rising, always try to top the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Look, he's on top.
[SPEAKER_00]: All that was a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Buzz is dead now.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's died many afters.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I saw what he taught me at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_00]: I looked for the ball right there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I knew that's where he was going to throw it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had good control.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit over the right field from the wall and the right field and beat him.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was a big skill.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was that in 1934 probably?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that's when Diz found me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I started around the bases and Diz found me all around the bases.
[SPEAKER_00]: He called me everything all the way around the bases.
[SPEAKER_00]: He couldn't make me mad then.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was great.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, that was the year the Cardinals had that great team, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's Cubs won it in 35.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: 35, that's in 35.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you with them then, or?
[SPEAKER_02]: That was the year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went to the Cubs in the latter part of 35.
[SPEAKER_00]: They played Detroit that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went out to play the World Series.
[SPEAKER_00]: I like one day from being there.
[SPEAKER_00]: In time, the BLs were playing the World Series.
[SPEAKER_00]: I missed out on that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was out in the Cub, the rest was 35 and 36.
[SPEAKER_00]: This was in 36 when I was...
[SPEAKER_00]: I think we finished top in second place with St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, the Giants won that game.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Giants won the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: Terry.
[SPEAKER_02]: Kind of a guy with Hack Wilson.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was gone.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went there with a guy named Glenn, Jim Ray, and Stanback, and old John Steadbaker.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was his name?
[SPEAKER_02]: Lindstrom.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Lindstrom.
[SPEAKER_00]: Missed them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Played center field, then left field, then we're in right field.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they had a climb.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I was there too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Tough climb.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some great experiences you've had, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I had a lot of fun in baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: I enjoyed it very much.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you have any feeling why you weren't up longer in the big time?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wasn't too good at outfielding, but I've always been a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: I just happened to be one of those things, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's always some pretty good people in front of you, it seems like, too, in the outfield.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I had some pretty good competition when I was up there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Nick Collip, when we... Yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you remember much about him?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I knew...
[SPEAKER_00]: He was there one evening with me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played against him in the Southern League here with Atlanta.
[SPEAKER_00]: When he was managing Milwaukee, I played...
[SPEAKER_00]: It happened when he was managing Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was on Columbus, too, when I...
[SPEAKER_00]: Columbus, Ohio and the American Association.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've talked to him a couple of times.
[SPEAKER_02]: He lives in Columbus now.
[SPEAKER_00]: He does?
[SPEAKER_02]: He's got a bad leg.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, well, I got a new hip put in.
[SPEAKER_00]: A complete hip, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: With separations and X-rays showed, but them wasn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: They got to hurt me here.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was in the Philippines for about, well, 18 years.
[SPEAKER_00]: I worked with Johnny Beasley.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess you know Johnny Beasley.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, the Cardinal pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he had his agency here for Falstaff for a long time.
[SPEAKER_02]: I have people I interview.
[SPEAKER_02]: I like to have them sign the ball here for me.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's a Kent Greenfield signed yesterday.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he was.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sign any place on there, please.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think that pen works.
[SPEAKER_02]: Kind of hard to write on that thing.
[SPEAKER_02]: I often wondered how the
[SPEAKER_02]: The ballplayers did it when they had so many to sign.
[SPEAKER_02]: Babe Ruth was the best I ever saw to sign a ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever see him sign a ball?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was told that he didn't sign those.
[SPEAKER_02]: Somebody else signed them for him.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I've seen him sign them.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: I think he had a stamp after a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: He hadn't signed so damn many, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was told that Art Fletcher, or Charlie O'Leary,
[SPEAKER_02]: He still signed a lot of his things.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever get to talk to the babe much?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember when I was in Albany, the only thing he ever said to me was, he come in with a sliding catch off of me on a line drive, and I was going out to left field, he was coming in from right field, and he said,
[SPEAKER_00]: Sorry, kid.
[SPEAKER_02]: Everybody was a kid, wasn't they?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he was the greatest, so Ruth was, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hank Hamlin, of course, was a great ball player.
[SPEAKER_00]: No doubt about that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I don't think anybody compared with Ruth.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you see Cobb play much, or at all?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he was the man of Detroit when I first went to Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he was over at Athletic.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a little while.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he was...
[SPEAKER_00]: He was about as true to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a hard time breaking in at Detroit ball clubs, even Carlton.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when they had Farley Gill and... Harry Heilman.
[SPEAKER_00]: Harry Heilman and... Somebody else getting about 400.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Manny Manouche, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, Manny Manouche was one of them.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, this matter of which Kent Greenfield mentioned about his drinking, how did they do much of this during Prohibition?
[SPEAKER_00]: Up in that part, of course, there was plenty of whiskey at any time.
[SPEAKER_02]: The old revenuers had trouble with it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was a lot of drinking among ballplayers, as far as you recall?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I think so.
[SPEAKER_02]: Some did, some didn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: Most were on the big league, and then the minor.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did the managers try to keep it in check, or they?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: They didn't approve of it, of course, but.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess it's.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like Harley Bolton, he had a reputation for drinking.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't drink much.
[SPEAKER_00]: He couldn't drink.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd have five, six rackets and he'd go crazy nuts.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's how he used to be.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't get in so much trouble by drinking and everything like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: His wife just died here last year.
[SPEAKER_02]: When did he die?
[SPEAKER_00]: He's been dead about five years now.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a heart attack.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was coaching Vanderbilt when he died.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he go to Vanderbilt?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: He went to, I'd say, some part of Louisiana.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where he's from, Louisiana.
[SPEAKER_00]: He married a nice little girl there and made his home here.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you know Johnny Gooch?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah, Johnny.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know Johnny, Charlie Goops, I know he's in that book, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that a brother of his?
[SPEAKER_02]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Johnny and I, we were talking the other day about him.
[SPEAKER_00]: that factory out here after a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was talking to a fellow, the president of this lumberyard out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Gooch used to have his office right next to it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was in that lumberyard and he was talking about Gooch.
[SPEAKER_00]: He thought a lot of Gooch.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, yeah, I said,
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, he'd probably be here today if he'd do nothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was going against the doctor's orders.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, hell, he wouldn't pay no attention to anybody, though.
[SPEAKER_00]: How about Red Lucas?
[SPEAKER_00]: Red?
[SPEAKER_00]: Red's still in town.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see Red?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I couldn't reach him.
[SPEAKER_02]: I guess he's around, but he wasn't home.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he lives on Greenwood Avenue or somewhere out there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I gave him a call, but I couldn't reach him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Red's still around.
[SPEAKER_00]: I see him every once in a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: I go to old town with him or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Baseball, yeah, we have a year here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Red's always there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you have any, in your years in minor league ball, in the majors too, are there any parks you like to play in particularly more than others?
[SPEAKER_02]: Are they all pretty much the same?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I think so.
[SPEAKER_02]: Had some great old parks.
[SPEAKER_00]: I liked the Chattanooga ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was a good ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: Good playing field in Chattanooga.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you retired from baseball about 1940, 1946 or so?
[SPEAKER_00]: Let's see.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think I managed to.
[SPEAKER_00]: You used to sit in 42.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think that was last year, I remember.
[SPEAKER_02]: How'd you like managing?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I went through a bad time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And all the inexperienced ballplayers had to come out of the Army.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I had a bad ball club start with.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think the second day of the season, I had to pitch a third baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: He went one too hard.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a good experience, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, it was an experience.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was in the kiddie league, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: 42.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was there a fellow named Jim Mills in the league that year, do you remember?
[SPEAKER_00]: Jim Mills?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I don't think so.
[SPEAKER_02]: Guess he may have been a rarier.
[SPEAKER_02]: So what'd you do then after you, uh... That's when I went to work for Beasley.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when he first took me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the brewery branch, he worked for the brewery.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I worked for him for quite some time.
[SPEAKER_00]: In the last two years, I worked for Ellis Cook over at the Fat Blue Ribbon.
[SPEAKER_02]: Salesman, you travel around?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: How long you been retired now?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I've been about six years now.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when I, when I had the hip operation about six years ago, that's when I retired.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you still have an interest in baseball?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, I like to, I watch all games on television.
[SPEAKER_00]: I haven't got baseball hair anymore.
[SPEAKER_00]: I watch the Sandlot players.
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you get the sporting news at all?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I haven't had a sport news in quite a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to get it all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not much baseball in it anymore.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, it was all football and other sports.
[SPEAKER_00]: All the sports that are in there now.
[SPEAKER_02]: Isn't like it used to be when Taylor Spink had it.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was all baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: And during the winter months would just be, where there's no other sports really, just be solid baseball news.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now in the winter months and sporting news, there's very little baseball news.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's not what it used to be.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you keep a scrapbook?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, I kept one.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think I tore away a lot of stuff the other day.
[SPEAKER_00]: You did?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh dear.
[SPEAKER_02]: I collect all those old things.
[SPEAKER_02]: You don't have anything laying around still, do you?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got something up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I forgot what it was.
[SPEAKER_02]: Got any pictures or anything I could see of your playing days?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, actually, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let's see if I can get this thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, that was, in effect, the end of the interview, although some things came on later, which might have been good to have the tape on.
[SPEAKER_01]: But everything was packed away by that time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, this is Tuesday evening.
[SPEAKER_01]: August 2, 1977.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm in the bathroom of a motel room in Nashville, Tennessee.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm in here because I didn't want to disturb Kathy and Rita in the room while I make these comments on this interview.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, let me review the day's activities.
[SPEAKER_01]: We stayed last night, August 1, in Clarksville.
[SPEAKER_01]: about 50 miles northwest of Nashville, where I'd hoped to interview Horace Lizenby.
[SPEAKER_01]: We got in our room there and all ready to set up an interview.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I called up, and he couldn't see me.
[SPEAKER_01]: So there we were.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had the Kent Greenfield interview that afternoon.
[SPEAKER_01]: But the plan was to come in here to Nashville, and today see Rad Lucas.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had planned to see Johnny Gooch and Red Lucas, but Gooch was dead.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we got in to see Lucas.
[SPEAKER_01]: We went out to his house.
[SPEAKER_01]: We found him without much trouble on the north side of town.
[SPEAKER_01]: But no one was there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I talked to a neighbor lady who said she didn't think they had left town.
[SPEAKER_01]: In fact, she was pretty sure, but she couldn't see why they weren't there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Lucas is a widower now.
[SPEAKER_01]: His wife has died last spring.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he made a daughter who's a schoolteacher who lives with him there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And she said he was very nice and would probably like to have an interview.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he wasn't there.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we then left and went around town, went to the Hermitage, Andrew Jackson's home, passed it by Grand Ole Opry Land, or Opry Land, USA, a fabulous Disney World type of amusement center on the north edge of town.
[SPEAKER_01]: They're building a new Grand Ole Opry house
[SPEAKER_01]: There was a tremendous motel there, which was a holiday inn, so pale beside it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Went on to the Hermitage, spent an hour or so there.
[SPEAKER_01]: We didn't go through the building because of the Hermitage itself, because such a line of tourists right up there would have taken an hour of just waiting in line.
[SPEAKER_01]: We didn't really feel worth that.
[SPEAKER_01]: We went and saw the film of Jackson's life and visited the other sites
[SPEAKER_01]: It didn't go through the museum.
[SPEAKER_01]: It went through the hermitage.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then we headed south.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's long, about 1230, quarter to 1.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now we're going to go to Days Inn on the eastern outskirts of Nashville.
[SPEAKER_01]: Usually, this is our basis of operations.
[SPEAKER_01]: We went to Days Inn, but they were all filled up and then derped us.
[SPEAKER_01]: going very early in the afternoon, no business for them to be filled up.
[SPEAKER_01]: Besides, today's was a budget motel.
[SPEAKER_01]: We thought we'd be able to save more money than that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, we left there.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was getting hot, very warm.
[SPEAKER_01]: Went on our way back towards town a little bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: That stays in being 12, 15 miles outside of town on the east end.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we got into, found this place here, the Expressway Motel.
[SPEAKER_01]: About 41, which is maybe 7 or 8 miles, maybe not quite so far out from the main part of town, a little bit southeast by southeast, something like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: In the afternoon, we went later after we got cooled off and fed, we went into town to see the Grand, or the Country Music Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_01]: a big building and all kinds of exhibits and plaques, gold star records, clothing worn by the stars, and a country music hall of fame.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was amusing and entertaining, but I still can't believe it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you know, right across the street from the place there, it's a vacant lot now at the east side, which says, there will rise here in the future, the gospel music hall of fame.
[SPEAKER_01]: What do you think of that?
[SPEAKER_01]: They also have here a Nashville Songwriters Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_01]: Crazy.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we came back.
[SPEAKER_01]: And meanwhile, at the motel, I tried a couple of times again to call Lucas, and still no answer.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I began to think there's somebody else around Nashville.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had on my list, but I eliminated because I wanted Lucas and Gooch were the top ones.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I looked on the list, and there was Johnny Gill.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I checked over his address and found it wasn't too far away.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I called him up, and he was nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a little hard of hearing, but he's, you know, he'd be willing to talk.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I planned to go out there about 7.30.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we went down at 8, around 6, and came back.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I left here to go over to Gil's house and got there about 7.30 in Sweetbriar, a little bit southwest of the center of town.
[SPEAKER_01]: nice residential neighborhood there, quiet.
[SPEAKER_01]: The old house.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he came out to greet me.
[SPEAKER_01]: So the interview ran for about an hour, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: The first half, the first slide, this tape fairly solid, but then it began to thin out on this side, as one can readily tell.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let me check this.
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_01]: We sat out on the back patio.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was daylight for about an hour.
[SPEAKER_01]: It began to get kind of dark a little later, so we turned the light on.
[SPEAKER_01]: We sat out on the back patio.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was daylight for about an hour.
[SPEAKER_01]: It began to get kind of dark a little later, so we turned the light on.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a tall man, six foot, the encyclopedia says 6'2 and 190 pounds.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's tall, he doesn't look that heavy now.
[SPEAKER_01]: Gray hair, he has most of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: He reminded me a little bit of Randolph Downs, the historian at Toledo University, with his wavy dark hair and the shape of his face.
[SPEAKER_01]: and his manner a little bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was soft-spoken, pleasant drawl, was a little hard of hearing, not too articulate.
[SPEAKER_01]: Memory was a little hazy here and there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Didn't have too much to say.
[SPEAKER_01]: Generally, this was a rather difficult interview.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was much more that I'm sure he could have said, but he just wasn't there.
[SPEAKER_01]: and easy conversations.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was very nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had a nice chat.
[SPEAKER_01]: But it was kind of hard getting things out of him, as you can readily see.
[SPEAKER_01]: He jumped around a little bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was kind of hard keeping things in track.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I finally gave up after a while.
[SPEAKER_01]: I just zeroed in on a few broad questions.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I don't think he was too successful.
[SPEAKER_01]: would be a good one to use as a test for students to see how they would have handled some of these things.
[SPEAKER_01]: His wife was not there.
[SPEAKER_01]: The house was being torn up.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said he was painting and redecorating it later.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's certainly true.
[SPEAKER_01]: He signed the ball for me.
[SPEAKER_01]: After I asked about pictures, he went and came out
[SPEAKER_01]: a two-frame pictures in a joint frame, about 8 by 10 where the frame is hinged and you close it like a book.
[SPEAKER_01]: Two 8 by 10 pictures of himself as a Chicago Cub.
[SPEAKER_01]: There wasn't enough light outside, even though they had the overhead light on, so we went in and I took those with a 35 millimeter camera and they probably won't come out.
[SPEAKER_01]: I also took a picture of himself standing with an oil painting of him
[SPEAKER_01]: done by his wife.
[SPEAKER_01]: The place is filled with oil paintings, she does.
[SPEAKER_01]: This was a very nice recent portrait of himself sitting comfortably in a rocking chair.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I've got a picture of him holding that picture.
[SPEAKER_01]: He also signed for me and gave me three postcard-sized cards, much like those Jim Rowe cards that I have, two with the Cubs uniform.
[SPEAKER_01]: one in Washington.
[SPEAKER_01]: He sent those for me.
[SPEAKER_01]: He, as he indicated, he had some stuff packed away.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't know where it was, though, so he wasn't much hope for that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mrs. Gill, as I said, wasn't there.
[SPEAKER_01]: But after we went in, I asked him if she would come down.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd like to meet her.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he called when she finally came down upstairs.
[SPEAKER_01]: She'd been upstairs.
[SPEAKER_01]: resting, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: She was a small woman.
[SPEAKER_01]: She had blonde hair and very pleasant.
[SPEAKER_01]: She's a Nashville gal.
[SPEAKER_01]: They have this very pleasant speaking pattern.
[SPEAKER_01]: Very nice, hospitable.
[SPEAKER_01]: And she knew my name and where she got it from.
[SPEAKER_01]: I just said it that once on the phone a second ago.
[SPEAKER_01]: She answered the phone, and I said, Jane Murdoch.
[SPEAKER_01]: The only time I said it, she picked it up because she came downstairs, Mr. Murdoch.
[SPEAKER_01]: So she remembered it.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I complimented her on her paintings.
[SPEAKER_01]: Remember that?
[SPEAKER_01]: It was not always the right thing to do, but they were nice paintings.
[SPEAKER_01]: So she came out in the back.
[SPEAKER_01]: She wanted to hear part of the tape.
[SPEAKER_01]: and I played about the last 10 minutes of the first side of this tape.
[SPEAKER_01]: She was quite interested in that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I began packing my gear away, and we talked generally.
[SPEAKER_01]: She would have been a good one to have in the interview, because she was quite a much freer talker, had more initiative in the conversation, and would have been able to fill in a lot of gaps and to spur his recollections.
[SPEAKER_01]: A couple of things she said.
[SPEAKER_01]: when the portion of the tape came up about his being thrown out of games.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, oh, two or three, maybe a three or four standard.
[SPEAKER_01]: She said about the time the first game she went to, which he played, where he was thrown out of the game, she said, oh, she was so embarrassed.
[SPEAKER_01]: She thought this was dreadful.
[SPEAKER_01]: She wanted to hide.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then she found out it wasn't so unusual for him to be thrown out of the game.
[SPEAKER_01]: So she didn't think it was quite so bad.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was horrified that first time.
[SPEAKER_01]: She said she did go to a lot of the games.
[SPEAKER_01]: Joe, I didn't know much about baseball before, but I traveled occasionally with the club, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: They got married in 1932 when he was with Chattanooga, I believe.
[SPEAKER_01]: Although she was not from there.
[SPEAKER_01]: She's from Nashville.
[SPEAKER_01]: They have no children.
[SPEAKER_01]: He expressed great interest in the tape.
[SPEAKER_01]: I offered to make a copy and send it to her for that, and she didn't want me to.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I'll go out of my way to do this, but I volunteered to do it, so I will.
[SPEAKER_01]: They don't have a recorder, but I said, well, maybe something you know has one you can borrow.
[SPEAKER_01]: Or you're not really that expensive.
[SPEAKER_01]: Maybe you want to have one at your home.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I guess this was a new experience to have, being on tape like this.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, she was chatting about various things.
[SPEAKER_01]: And asked me about Warren Harding, if he wasn't from my town.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, no, he's Marian, not Marietta.
[SPEAKER_01]: Chatted a little bit about Harding.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mentioned what a great baseball fan he was, how he would have the stars of the day come to the White House for dinner and chat with the president.
[SPEAKER_01]: We'd talk about all his years out in the Pacific Coast League.
[SPEAKER_01]: Lefty, she says, she asked, did he tell you about playing for Lefty O'Doul?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, no, when I was out in San Francisco.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said about that time, I said, I think I better put this tape back on and interview you, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: I remember a lot of these things.
[SPEAKER_01]: She chuckled and said, no, I don't remember much.
[SPEAKER_01]: We'll talk now a little bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Fifteen, twenty minutes more out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was sipping the lemonade he brought, delicious glass of lemonade.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, sorry I didn't have any more, but this is a teetotaling house.
[SPEAKER_01]: Which reminded me of something else that came up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: How she said that something to this effect, Johnny's career would have been
[SPEAKER_01]: lasted much longer if he was such a playboy, something like that, which, of course, I didn't learn about.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't mention it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he says, well, you're probably right.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wasn't like Kent Greenfield, he talked about earlier, who drank himself out of the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I had my fun.
[SPEAKER_01]: So there's something there which, if I'd known about, I might have pursued a little bit had the tape been on.
[SPEAKER_01]: Apparently, he enjoyed himself in baseball, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: And of course, invited me to come back any time and I said, maybe write them before coming down again and they can dig out some of the scrapbooks or whatever they do have packed away, which he doesn't know where it is right now, but they do have something.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mentioned a Minor League record book, which Saber's putting out, and what the idea that was, and that he would begin
[SPEAKER_01]: She mentioned that, Johnny, didn't you get something from somebody about your minor league record, trying to fill in some gaps?
[SPEAKER_01]: She says, I think that's what it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were putting together this book, and they wanted more information from you.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd forgotten it, but this, remember, this recalled it to his mind.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, yes, I think that's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I told him they would certainly get a copy when that came out.
[SPEAKER_01]: I want to make sure that happens if they don't get one.
[SPEAKER_01]: Through ordinary channels, we don't hear about it, that somebody does contact them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Anything else happen there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Those were the main things.
[SPEAKER_01]: He spoke about his artificial hip, which he had put in.
[SPEAKER_01]: He walks with something of a limp.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he can paint his house and be decorated.
[SPEAKER_01]: He must be in pretty good shape.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can't think of much more to say at this time, so I think I will sign off and perhaps use the rest of the tape for some comment on one of the other interviews we have come with.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tomorrow, on August 3rd, we're going to travel down to Alabama, perhaps go to the Huntsville Space Center, and then on to Tuscaloosa, where on Thursday, the 4th of August, I'm due to have the interview with Joey Sewell, and hopefully Rick Stevens.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I know Sewell's all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: I suggest Stevens will be, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll have to wait and see.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's all for today, August 2nd.
[SPEAKER_01]: 1977.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's about 11.30 at night now.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm signing off from the bathroom of our Expressway Motel in Nashville, Tennessee.